Guide to the The Good Fight: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War: Audiotapes ALBA.AUDIO.216
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Interviews, 1979-1988; 10 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 5 flat boxes,1 manuscript box, and 1 CD box
  - Gabriel "Jack" Quiones, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_295)
  - Nick Pappas, circa 1980-1983; cuid44907
    - Tape 1, cuid44904 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_116)
    - Tape 2, cuid44905 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_117)
    - Tape 3, cuid44906 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_118)
  - Stanley Postek, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_145)
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_146)
    - #3 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_147)
    - #4 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_148)
  - Mildred Rackley Simon, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_286)
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_287)
  - Bob Reed, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_332)
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_333)
  - Al Robbins, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_137)
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_138)
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_139)
    - #4, Bob Steck #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_140)
  - Will Roger Jr. -- 2nd Take, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_378)
  - Mary Rolfe, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_283)
  - Edna Romer, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_306)
  - Patrick Roosevelt, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_366)
    - Audio recording (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_368)
  - Gabby Rosenstein, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_122)
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_123)
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_124)
  - John Rossen, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_316)
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_317)
  - Bernard Rucker, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_166)
    - #2 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_167)
    - #3, Carl Geiser #1 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_168)
  - Bill Sennett, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_269)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_270)
  - Ken Shaker, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_299)
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_300)
  - Elias Schultz, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_337)
  - Ben Sills, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_275)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_276)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_277)
  - Pete Smith, circa 1980-1983
    - #2 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_155)
      For part one of this interview, see reel 216_154.
    - #3 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_156)
    - #4, Leonard Lamb #1 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_157)
  - Rose Sorkin and Michael Shantzek, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_326)
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_327)
  - Morris Stamm, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_312)
  - Fred Stanley, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_111)
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_112)
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_113)
    - #4 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_114)
    - #5 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_115)
  - Bob Steck, circa 1980-1983
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_141)
      For part one of this interview, see reel 216_140.
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_142)
    - #4 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_143)
    - #5 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_144)
  - Bill Susman, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_134)
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_135)
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_136)
  - Bob Taylor, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_320)
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_321)
  - Dave Thompson, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_017)
    - #2 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_018)
    - #3 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_019)
    - #4 (Box Shared Tamiment 204, Quarter inch audio reel 216_020)
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_291)
    - Audio recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_292)
  - Ralph Thornton, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_319)
  - Isadore Tivin and Fred Keller, circa 1980-1983
    - #2 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_109)
      For part one of this interview, see reel 216_108.
    - #3 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 216_110)
  - Earl Vail, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_170)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_171)
  - Bill Van Felix, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_164)
    - #2 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_165)
  - Theodore Velfort, May, 1988 (Box Shared Tamiment 115)
  - George Watt, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_389)
  - Alex Weinerman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_319)
  - Weissman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_373)
  - Saul Wellman, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_323)
    - Audio recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_324)
  - Bill Wheeler, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_301)
  - Milt Wolff, circa 1980-1983
    - #1 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_005)
    - #2 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_006)
    - #3 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_007)
    - #4 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_008)
    - #5 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_009)
    - #6 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_010)
    - #7 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_011)
    - #8 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_012)
    - #9 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_013)
    - #10 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_014)
    - #11 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_015)
    - #12 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 216_016)
    - II #1 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_087)
    - II #2 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_088)
    - II #3 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_089)
    - II #4 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_090)
    - II #5, Bill Bailey II #1 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_091)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_265)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_266)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_267)
  - Jimmy Yates, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_254)
    - Audio recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_255)
  - Joe Zanadowski and Paul Lutka, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_318)
- Series II. Event Recordings, 1966-1973; 2.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
  This series is arranged chronologically. Undated materials are arranged alphabetically.
  Series II. Event Recordings (1966-1973) contains event recordings, including Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade National Conferences, group meetings, and memorials.
  - Vets of Lincoln Brigade Group Meeting about Vietnam, August 9, 1966 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_246)
    Recording includes John Toutloff, Moe Fishman, Mark Alper, and John Koblick.
  - Memorial Meeting at Prince George Hotel, NY, December 6, 1970 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_398)
  - VALB Meeting at YMCA, November, 1972 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_405)
  - VALB National Conference YWCA, NY, February 11, 1973
    - Reel 1 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_400)
    - Reel 2 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_404)
  - Jackson's performance, USA (, ), undated (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_394)
  - VALB CCNY #1: National Anthem, Alice Chadler, Jennie Chakin, Intro remarks, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_187)
  - VALB CCNY #2: Colodny, Philip Foner, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_188)
  - VALB CCNY #3: Foner, Joseph Lash, Abraham Raskin, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_189)
  - VALB CCNY #4: Pete Smith, Jennie Chakin, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_190)
  - VALB CCNY #5: Jeanette Mendelson Dean, Herb Freeman, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_191)
  - VALB #6 Poetry readings: Pete Smith, Janine Hamilton, Edith Segal, Al Prago, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_192)
  - VALB #7 Poetry readings: Al Prago, M. Meehan, Jim Lally, Joe Doyle, Bob Steich, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_193)
  - VALB #8 Poetry readings: Bob Steich, Pete Smith, Janine Hamilton, Yates, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_194)
  - VALB #9 Poetry readings: Bob Steich, Geiser, Prago, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_195)
  - VALB #10 Poetry readings: Al Prago, song, Pete Smith, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_196)
  - VALB #11 Poetry readings: Pete Smith, Dorothy Ibarucci speech, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 216_197)
  - VALB 25th Anniversary, Lester Gittelson, undated (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_395)
  - The Winds of the People, A Memorial Commemorating the 25th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War, undated (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_397)
- Series III. Source Audio, 1937-1983; 4.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 flat boxes, 1 manuscript box, and 1 media box
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Series III. Source Audio (1937-1983) includes other audio recordings used in the production of the film, such as Studs Terkel's narration, radio broadcasts, musical recordings, speeches, and sound samples.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project, circa 1980-1983
    - Audio recordings (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_375)
    - Audio recordings (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_386)
    - Audio recordings (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_387)
    - Audio recordings (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_388)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Music Ideas, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_374)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Music Session 1, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_383)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Music Session 2, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_384)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Music Session 3, 1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_385)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade -- Music, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_376)
  - Al Toca Piaa, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_377)
  - "As It Happens," CBC Radio, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_379)
  - ALB Master Takes: Hemingway Speech (1947), National Archives, Renner's International, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_226)
  - ALB Songs, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_225)
  - British Movietone: Leon Bloom, Toledo Dead, Geinberg, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_240)
  - Dartmouth History Panel, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_251)
  - Broadcast Recording -- KPFK, KPFA, WBAI, April 17, 1962
    - Tape 1 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_401)
    - Tape 2 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_399)
  - El Salvador Demo, March 27, 1982
    - Audio recording (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_085)
    - Audio recording (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 216_086)
  - El Salvador Rally in Washington DC, 1982
    - Audio recording (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_212)
    - Boarding bus, vets on bus (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_210)
    - March with vets, lots of clapping (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_213)
    - Vets on bus (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_211)
  - From Vincent Voice Library, Coughlin, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_242)
  - Hellerman: "The Internationale", circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_380)
  - Hemingway, "To the Spanish Dead" (Box Shared Tamiment 115)
  - Hemingway tribute to vets, undated (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_406)
  - Interview with Moe Fishman and Louise Pettibone Smith on Barry Farber Show, June 30, 1964 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_403)
  - Interview with two Americans who fought in Spain (one Loyalist, one Rebel), March 20, 1938 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_232)
  - Isolationist Songs: Huey Long, Harry Williams, Mr. District Attorney " The Case of the Unknown Source", undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_243)
  - Italian songs, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_244)
  - La Brigada Internacional -- David Rees, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_241)
  - "Lincoln Brigade" Coleen Dewhurst, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_228)
  - Martha Gellhorn talks about the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (radio broadcast from Madrid), October 7, 1939 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_230)
  - Martha Gellhorn talks about life in Madrid during the war (radio broadcast from Madrid), April 19, 1937 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_231)
  - Max Parker: Three Songs, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_223)
  - Meeting of Veterans and their families at Times Sq. Hotel, Part of broadcast on WKCR by Tana de Gamez and Moe Fisher, 1969 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_407)
  - Moe, KPFK, August, 1968 (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_402)
  - Music from Brandeis, undated
    - Tape A: Spain 1936-1939, 25 Hymns (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_214)
    - Tape B: The Spanish Civil War 1936-1939, Men and Events of the 20th Century, Nationalist and Republican Voices and Songs (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_221)
    - Tape C: The Spanish Civil War 1936-1939, Men and Events of the 20th Century, Nationalist and Republican Voices and Songs (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_222)
  - Pete Seeger Concert, Dartmouth, April 17, 1981
    - Concert (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_209)
    - Interview, concert (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_207)
    - Transfer tape of Seeger's song with Vets, Rumbalala (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_208)
  - Radio Clip -- McDonald, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_245)
  - Radio Clip -- Spanish Civil War, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_227)
  - Saint Saens Marche Heroique, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_381)
  - Spanish Civil War Items from Reveille Museum, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_229)
  - Spanish Civil War Radio Clip from CBC, Ernest Hemingway introduction and "New Masses," "On the American Dead in Spain", undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_224)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #1, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_233)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #2, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_234)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #3, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_235)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #4, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_236)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #5, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_237)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #6, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_238)
  - Studs Terkel narrating Abraham Lincoln Brigade #7, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_239)
  - "They Shall Not Pass", circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_382)
  - Tones -- 3 Cymbal Hits, August 4, 1983 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 216_247)
  - Untitled ALBA Tape, undated (Box 6, Quarter inch audio reel 216_396)
    This tape features Steve Nelson (intro), Bob Steck, Tana de Gamez, Mike Glick (guitar), Moe Fishman, Maurice Bryer, Josefina Lang, Bill Chaleff, and Carey McWilliams.